I gave the village a cursory search, but…
我在村子里粗略地搜索了一下 但是
Nothing made sense.
这一切都没道理
The more I know, the less I can see the full picture…
我知道的越多 就越看不清全貌
Gabimaru?
画眉丸？
Is something wrong?
有什么不对吗？
It's nothing. So?
没什么 所以怎么了？
Ah, Senta-dono is…
仙汰他…
Apparently his brain maxed out.
很显然 他的脑子已经用尽了
There are so many mysteries…
谜团太多了
If I don't cool down my brain and organize it…
如果我再不让大脑冷静下来…
Please take a break, Senta-dono.
请休息一下吧 仙汰
I can take the night watch alone.
我能一个人守夜
No, no. I'm fine.
不 我没事
I'll be fine after a bath.
我洗个澡就好了
You'll be even more tired.
那样你会更累的
I'll be fine!
我会没事的！
There's so much we don't know…
有太多我们不知道的事
It's too dangerous to go on without learning more.
在没有足够了解前 就继续的话会很危险
How much more do we need to learn?
我们还需要了解多少？
That… I don't know.
那个…我不知道
However, if Lord Tensen is tasked with protecting the elixir of life,
然而 如果天仙大人的任务 是保护长生不老药
going to Horai without a plan would be dangerous.
毫无准备地去蓬莱会很危险
I'm sorry, but we don't have time to figure things out.
对不起 但我们没有时间 把一切都搞清楚
It would be faster just to draw them out.
直接把他们引出来会更快
The fog is so thick I can't see what's around me.
雾太大了 周围是什么都看不清楚
We found this village in the woods south of the sea.
我们在大海南边的树林里 发现了这个村子
If Hoko is to be believed,
如果木人是可信的
if we keep going south, we should get close to Horai in the center.
如果我们继续向南 应该就会接近蓬莱中心
What am I hearing? Singing?
我听到的是什么？歌声？
No…
不对
Sutras?
诵经？
Are they relatives of Hoko?
他们是木人的亲戚吗？
They aren't reacting to my presence.
他们对我的出现没有反应
Maybe they can't move.
也许他们动不了
They're praying to something…
他们在向什么东西祈祷
It's too dangerous to go on without learning more.
在没有足够了解前 就继续的话会很危险
That might be true for an Asaemon, but a sinner is different.
对于浅右卫门来说可能是这样 但罪人不同
I can't turn back just because the island is dangerous.
我不能因为这个岛很危险就回头
That's not what we're doing here.
那我不是我来这里的目的
No matter how dangerous it is…
不管有多危险
if I don't bring back the elixir, I won't get a pardon.
如果我不带回灵药 我就得不到赦免
My only choice is to keep going.
我唯一的选择就是继续前进
Even if I go alone.
即使是我一个人
They say the Horai region is beautiful even now.
他们说蓬莱区即使是现在也很美
Unlike the Hojo and Eishu regions,
与方丈、瀛洲地区不同
it is where the gods and the Sennin live.
那是众神和仙人居住的地方
It is the real Shinsenkyo.
那是真正的神仙境
The "real Shinsenkyo"?
“真正的神仙境”？
It looks manmade.
它看起来是人造的
If this is Horai, the elixir could be here…
如果这里是蓬莱 那长生不老药应该在这里
What? Something's off…
什么？有点不对劲
She looks human, but she's something else…
她看起来像人类 但她是别的什么
Who are you?
你是谁？
Man, I quit.
天啊 我要辞职
Why is it always on my turn? So annoying.
为什么一直轮到我？真讨厌
Hey, can't you just leave?
喂 你直接离开行不行？
I just did this.
我这么做了
If I see any humans like you, I have to capture them, you know.
如果见到你这样的人类 我就得抓住他们 懂吗？
It had to be me today…
今天必须是我来
Is it… to turn humans into the elixir?
是把人类变成长生不老药吗？
Oh?
哦！
She has regenerative abilities…
她有再生的能力
and more strength and speed than she should have.
超常的力量和速度
She must be a…
她一定是个…
My neck again?
又是我的脖子？
Ninja Art: Fire Monk!
忍术：火僧
Did I kill him again?
我又杀了他了吗？
If I'd brought him in, he would have made an excellent Tan.
如果我把他带进来 他会成为很好的“棕褐色”
This might be bad timing…
也许这不是个好时机
But are you Lord Tensen?
但你是天仙大人吗？
Are you human?
你是人类吗？
How are you holding up so well?
你怎么坚持得这么好？
The last guy was pretty tenacious too.
上一个家伙也很顽强
But I haven't seen someone like you in centuries.
但像你这样的 我已经几个世纪没见过了
Where is the elixir?
长生不老药在哪里？
I should probably consider any attacks or blows useless.
我也许应该把任何攻击 都当做是无用的
His arm strength is exceptional.
他的臂力非比寻常
If this fight goes on, he'll wear me down.
如果继续下去 他会把我累垮的
I'll have to find a quick way to take him out.
我得想个办法快速把他击倒
He's an immortal… Fire Monk had no effect.
他是仙人 火僧没有任何效果
What haven't I tried yet?
还有什么我没有试过？
I need something!
是什么呢？
What… was that reaction?
那是什么反应？
That was completely different from other times.
跟前几次完全不同
What happened? What worked?
发生什么了？是什么起作用了？
He turned back into a woman.
他又变回了女人
That strength of yours…
你的力量…
I don't think you know, but it's probably…
我想你不知道 但那可能是…
No, it doesn't matter.
不 那不重要
You're pissing me off. Die.
你令我很生气 去死吧
What is this?
那是什么？
Wind pressure? No.
风压？不
Every attack feels like it echoes inside me.
每一次攻击都感觉像是在我体内回荡
It's some other kind of unknown power…
是一种未知的力量
Guarding is… useless… Can't… dodge…
防御没用 无法闪避
Is there no way to take her down fast?
没有办法迅速击倒她吗？
I don't need one!
我不需要
I don't have time…
我没有时间
to stand around and think of one!
站在原地思考！
I have to get back to my wife!
我得回到我妻子身边！
I'll do what I must to survive and return to her.
我会尽我所能活着回到她身边
Even if I lose my eyes or nose, I'm going back alive!
即使是失去眼睛或鼻子 我也要活着回去
Even if I die, I'm going back alive!
即使我死了 我也要活着回去
I'll just have to destroy her faster than she can regenerate.
我只需要在她重生之前彻底摧毁她
Impossible… A human can't…
不可能 一个人类不可能…
You're probably still not dead, so answer me.
你也许还没有死 所以回答我
Where is the elixir?
长生不老药在哪里？
What should I do?
我该怎么办？
They'll get mad at me again.
他们又该生我的气了
Stay calm.
保持冷静
It's not the first time you've faced a monster.
这不是你第一次面对怪物了
Analyze and deal,
分析处理
just like always. Then…
就像往常那样 然后…
Ninja Art: Fire Monk.
忍术：火僧
My body…
我的身体…
All it's endured is finally catching up to me.
我忍着的一切终于追上我了
Mysterious magic and huge monsters…
神秘的魔法和巨大的怪物
Is all this really real?
这一切都是真实的吗？
No… Was anything from the past few days real?
不 这几天发生的一切是真实的吗？
It's like I'm having a nightmare.
就好像我做了个噩梦
Are you awake?
你醒了？
You were thrashing about.
你刚才在挣扎
Did you have a bad dream?
你做噩梦了吗？
Oh…
哦
I guess…
也许是吧
A dream…
是个梦啊
Thank goodness.
谢天谢地
You must have had a nightmare.
你一定是做噩梦了
You've been so busy lately.
你最近太忙了
Why don't you take today to rest?
今天就休息吧？
Have some chrysanthemum tea.
喝点洋甘菊
I've heard it prevents nightmares.
我听说它可以防止做噩梦
Oh dear… Do you not like chrysanthemum?
天啊 你不喜欢洋甘菊？
It's not that. I'm just really happy.
不是那样的 我只是非常开心
Even if this is just a dream…
就算这只是个梦
I'm glad I get to talk to you.
我也很高兴能跟你说话
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢？
I'm sorry.
对不起
I might not be able to come home after all.
我也许回不了家了
The Law of the Shinobi, rule number 20.
《忍者法则》第20条
If you are on the verge of death,
如果你在死亡边缘
muster the last of your life force
鼓起你最后的生命力
to deal as much damage as possible before your death.
在你死前造成尽可能多的伤害
Well, just memorize it.
记住了
I have trained the instinct into you either way.
无论哪种方式 我都将本能训练到你身上
If it comes to your death, aim to make it a draw.
如果涉及到你的死亡 目标是平局
It has nothing to do with desire.
这与欲望无关
I'm sorry… I might…
对不起 我可能…
Mei… What are you doing?
梅 你在干什么？
We can't help what's already been done.
我们无法帮助已经发生的事情
I… I'm so sorry!
对…对不起！
I searched for him immediately, but…
我立刻去搜寻他了 但是…
The fog got thicker the farther from the village I got.
我越是深入村子 雾越大
Even coming back was a trial…
我差点都回不来了
It is impossible to advance in a straight line through that fog.
在迷雾中想要直线前进是不可能的
For an ordinary human, anyway.
至少对普通人类来说是这样
If Gabimaru was headed for the Horai region…
如果画眉丸去了蓬莱区…
We'd better find him soon.
我们最好快点找到他
-I don't want to! -What?
-我不想去 -什么？
We don't have time for that!
我们没有时间做那个
He left all on his own.
他一个人离开了
He was useful in battle,
他在战斗中很有用
but we can't help it if he left.
但他走了我们也没办法
Besides, why should an Asaemon care
再说 浅右卫门为什么
about the safety of a sinner?
要在乎一个罪人的安危？
There's really no reason to find him.
实在没有该去找他的理由
Ah, well…
那个…
If you mean to go to Horai, I will accompany you.
如果你说的是去蓬莱 我跟你一起去
I cannot find Mei anywhere.
我到处都找不到梅
I think she must have followed Gabimaru.
我想她一定跟着画眉丸
I must go find her, but I would like some assistance.
我得去找她 但我需要一些帮助
So does that mean you can navigate through the fog?
你的意思是说你能穿越迷雾？
I can.
我可以
Well, then! I too, am-- am--
那么其实我也
Worried! I, too, am worried about Gabimaru! Let's go together, Sagirin!
很担心画眉丸 我们一起去吧 佐切
Very well.
好
But, enough about going to Horai.
说了那么多去蓬莱的事
Doesn't Lord Tensen have some nasty guys around him?
天仙大人身边没有讨厌的家伙吗？
Correct.
没错
What is Lord Tensen?
天仙大人是什么？
Tell us more about him!
再说说关于他的事吧
Miss Yuzuriha, you'll get lost if you don't focus.
杠小姐 你不集中精力的话会迷路的
No, I won't!
不会的
-Sagirin, you want to know too, right? -Huh?
-佐切 你也想知道吧？ -嗯？
About Lord Tensen.
关于天仙大人
Yes. I do.
是的 没错
If Lord Tensen lives in Horai,
如果天仙大人住在蓬莱
I'm sure we will cross paths eventually.
我肯定我们最终会遇上的
Lord Tensen is…
天仙大人是
The Seven Sennin.
七仙人
A man is better.
男人更好
To start with, he has no extra parts.
首先 他没有多余的部分
His beauty is in the simplicity of design.
他的美在于设计的简洁
I much prefer women.
我更喜欢女人
When I see a female body, I just want to touch it.
当我看到女性的身体时 我只想触摸它
Shut up.
闭嘴
Both are beautiful in their own way.
都有各自不同的美
Are we only talking about looks?
我们只说外表吗？
I prefer men.
我更喜欢男人
Their condition and operation are more natural.
他们的状态和操作更自然
What? Last time you agreed with me.
什么？上一次你同意了我的说法
That was based on interest.
那是基于兴趣
Not true! You were so passionate about it.
不是真的 你对它很热情的
You're good at handling cranky people.
你擅长对付脾气暴躁的人
That's what's great about him!
这就是他的厉害之处
It's good to be so lively.
这么热闹真好
Shut up.
闭嘴
Enough chit-chat.
别闲聊了
I will begin my regular report.
我要开始我的常规报告了
The humans that arrived on the island the other day
前几天到达岛上的人类
appear to be different from those who came before.
似乎与之前来过的那些有所不同
They are fewer, but fiercer.
人更少 但更凶猛
They have killed many Soshin.
他们已经杀了很多宗慎
Zhu Jin, it's because you've been slacking on watch!
朱槿 都是因为你没有好好看守
You allowed the humans we found at the beach to slip by.
你让我们在海滩上发现的人类溜走了
And last night you had a close battle with another at the gate.
昨晚你在门口跟另一个人近身战斗
You're pathetic!
你真可悲！
What's more, you're in that form.
甚至 你还在那种形态
You used too much Tao.
你用了太多道
Oh dear.
天啊
You reap what you sow.
种瓜得瓜 种豆得豆
I can't believe you were so cornered you had to use your Kishikai.
真不敢相信你走投无路到 要用你的鬼尸解
That's enough, Ju Fa. We are a family.
够了 菊花 我们是一家人
Family must be united.
家人要团结
And family must obey.
家人必须服从
They must obey me.
他们必须服从我
I am the only one allowed to harm Zhu Jin.
只有我一个人可以伤害朱瑾
Fine.
好吧
What about the human you encountered in the forest?
你们在森林里遇到的人类呢？
Did you take care of him?
解决他们了吗？
I dropped him half-dead in a hole.
我把他丢在一个洞里 半死不活的
He must be flowers by now.
他现在一定已经变成花了
Don't get cocky.
别太得意
We have also discovered a corpse in front of the gate.
我们在门口也发现了一具尸体
A human who could kill that should not be underestimated.
能杀死那个的人不容小觑
Including the human who cornered Zhu Jin last night…
再加上把朱槿逼到绝境的那个人
Something is different this time.
这一次有些不同
If he manages to escape from the hole…
如果他设法从洞里逃了出来
There's reason to fear an injured beast.
害怕受伤的野兽是有道理的
If the humans who he arrived with are of similar strength,
如果来这里的人类都实力相近
we may be in some trouble.
我就会有麻烦了
The man who made you use your Kishikai…
那个让你使用鬼尸解的人
You made sure to kill him, right?
你确定要杀了他 对吧？
Yeah…
是
Well, whoever comes,
那么 不管谁来
we are of one mind.
我们都是一条心
To immortal Soshi.
献给不朽的宗慎
There are actually seven immortals?
居然有七位仙人？
It is said that there was originally only one.
据说那里原本只有一个
What? What does that mean?
什么？这是什么意思？
Shangdi Samantabhadra, Great Emperor Akshobhya,
普贤上帝、阿閦大帝
Enthroned Amoghavajra, Great Sage Ratna,
不空就君、宝生大圣
Tathata Yuanjun, Decorous Monju Koko, Imperial Monarch Cundi.
如意元君、文殊公公、准胝帝君
A Sennin climbed a mountain and became a god,
一个仙人爬上了山成为神
then split into seven.
然后分裂成了七个
They all have the same appearance and voice.
他们都有同样的声音和样貌
But their personalities and roles differ.
但他们的性格和角色不同
These seven rule over this island.
这七位统治着这个岛屿
That is the limit of what I have known since I was a child.
我就知道这么多 那时候我还是个孩子
When you were a child…
当你是个孩子的时候
were you a leaf?
你是一片树叶吗？
No.
不是
I bore the same appearance as you.
我出生时跟你们一样
All who live in the village once bore human-like appearances.
所有住在村子里的人 都曾拥有类似人类的外表
We lived longer than you, and were stronger in our faith.
我们活得比你们长 并且我们的信仰更加坚定
Our village prospered.
我们的村庄很繁荣
However…
然而…
Is this…?
这是…
It has been a thousand years since the village prospered.
村子繁荣的时候已经是一千年前了
Our lives may be long,
我们的生命可能很长
but before we die, we arborify.
但是死前 我们会树化
Arborify?
树化？
Our bodies slowly become trees.
我们的身体会慢慢变成树
In the end, we become a single tree
最后我们就变成了一棵树
and root down to the ground in a prayer position.
并以祈祷的姿势扎根于地面
It progresses regardless of age,
树化过程与年龄无关
and we lose our consciousness.
我们最后都会失去意识
Just before losing consciousness, we come here.
在失去意识之前 我们来到这里
In doing so, we believe
我们相信这样做的话
that our soul will then be invited to Horai.
我们的灵魂会被邀请到蓬莱
Very little of my consciousness remains.
我的意识所剩无几了
I had a family, but they have all aborified.
我有一个家庭 而他们都树化了
This is my daughter.
这是我的女儿
Unfortunately, she was the first in my family to arborify.
很不幸 她是我们家第一个树化的
In that case, even if you do live for over a thousand years,
这样的话 即使你们可以活一千年
the village would still decay.
村庄仍然会衰败
Horai is the goal for the soul, where it will find rest.
蓬莱是灵魂的目标 它会在那里安息
Lord Tensen are the gods who determines who enters Horai.
天仙大人是决定谁可以进入蓬莱的神
We must never disobey them.
我们绝不能违抗他们
He left without telling anyone…
他没有告诉任何人就离开了
And his welfare is out of my jurisdiction…
而他的安危不在我的管辖范围内
But…
但是
I still hope he's safe.
我依然希望他是安全的
Where… am I?
我们在哪里？
Did this girl save me?
是这个女孩救了我吗？
The Sennin… They can't possibly be gods.
仙人…他们不可能是神
They are monsters, plain and simple.
他们是怪物 简单明了
If I want to get the elixir…
如果想得到长生不老药
I'll have to kill one.
我必须得杀一个
Thank goodness.
太好了
If they're monsters and not gods…
如果他们是怪物而不是神
That means there's a way to kill them.
那就意味着我有办法杀他们了
But I can't be reckless. I'll have to find a way to fight them.
但我不能鲁莽 我得想办法对付他们
It'll be hard on my own.
我一个人的话会很难
I'll need two or three people… Maybe even more.
我需要两个或三个人 或许更多
I thought a pile of dirty rags was moving,
我以为是一堆脏破布在动
but it's just that ninja from before.
原来是刚才那个忍者
You look like hell. Someone do you in?
你看起来糟透了 被人打了？
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻译：朱未耒